

Yang, Bo

Developer



+1-415-420-9693



https://yang-bo.com



yang-bo@yang-bo.com



pop_atry



yang_bo



955091



Atry

About me -

I am a developer who knows how to create application frameworks.

I founded a number of open-source projects for creating micro-services, neural networks, reactive GUIs, and DSLs, which are stared 3000+ times on GitHub.

My current interests include machine learning infrastructure and the application of functional programming languages to real-world problems.

Skills -

Scala

Machine Learning

Software Design

Agile Project Management

Hack *5.5 Haxe *5.5 OpenCL *5 DevOps *5 ActionScript *4 C++ *4 Java *4 JavaScript *4 Rust *4 OCaml *4 Testing *3 C *3 Spark *3 Akka *3

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

Experience

Experien			
2023-	Preemo Inc As Preemo's only MLE, I conceptualized multitenancy service for fine-tune and infererence, and developed the whole API service sonely from scratch, known as https://gradient.ai, except for billing and authentication modules.		
2019-2022	Meta Platforms Inc I built machine learning infrastructure to detect payment fraud and in a variety of products. Then I joined the Hack/HHVM OSS team, where of maintaining HHVM's open-source branch.		
2015-2019	Thoughtworks Inc Senior Consultant / L I maintained a number of open-source projects sponsored by Thought Tech Lead, delivered various projects of mobile, web applications, and o	Vorks, and as a	
2014	Shenzhen QiFun Network Corp., LTD Chi I led the Q-Force Team in developing a game engine along with its rel two mobile games.	ef Programmer ated tools, and	
2011-2013	Shenzhen Putaoteng Network Technology Co., Ltd. I led the start-up team in developing a 3D side-scrolling game engine V social game Nan Da Nu Pei.	Co-founder inyHome and a	
2008-2011	NetEase, Inc. Chi I participated in various product teams as a developer or the technic ing Zhan Guo Feng Yun (web game), Ka Pai Dui Jue (web game), Deep engine).	,	
2007	Beijing HiPiHi Information Technology Corp.,Ltd Sof developed in the both server-side and client-side of the 3D virtual world	tware Engineer d, HiPiHi World.	
2006-2007	Beijing AutoNavi Software Co., Ltd. Sof As a developer, I developed some components for a 3D navigation soft	tware Engineer ware.	
Open-soi	urce projects		
2021-2022	HHVM is Meta's virtual machine to run Hack. I ported the open source bran NixOS and created CI pipeline for building, testing, and packaging HHV		
since 2018	Dsl.scala is a framework to extend Scala language features in libraries. I also por work to Haskell as Control.Dsl.	Scala ted this frame-	
since 2016	DeepLearning.scala and Compute.scala are libraries for creating complex neural networks.	Scala	
since 2015	Binding.scala is a reactive templating language for creating web and desktop GUI.	Scala	
2015-2016	Microbuilder Haxe / Scala / Ja is a toolkit to build system across micro-services implemented in vari communicating via RESTful JSON API.		
since 2012	haxe-continuation provides async/await syntax for Haxe.	Haxe	
since 2010	protoc-gen-as3 is a Protocol Buffers plugin for ActionScript 3.	ActionScript3	
since 2007	other 100+ of open-source projects		
Publicati	ons		
2017 2017	DeepLearning.scala 2.0: Statically Typed Neural Network More than React	S	

2017 2017 2009 Talks	DeepLearning.scala 2.0: Statically Typed Neural Networks More than React Adobe Flex 3: Training from the Source	translator
2017	Deeplearning.scala - Thoughts and practices on OSS AI framework	DBTC

Strange Loop

QCon · Beijing

ECUG Con

ArchData Summit · Beijing

Monadic Deep Learning

More than Async

Education

2017

2017

2016

2015

2002-2006 Southwest University of Political Science and Law Bachelor Of Laws

Specific-domain extension in an universal language

Neural Networks & Functional Programming